Is it that easy to adjust the
Uka-no-Mitama virus?
ウカノミタマ·ウイルスの調整ってのは
そう簡単にできるもんなのかね
作業工程自体は ほぼ全自動のはずですからね
The process itself should be
pretty much automated,
so as long as the
equipment still works, yes.
機材さえ生きていれば
They chose Uka-no-Mitama precisely
because of how easy it is to update.
そもそも アップデートの容易さがウカノミタマの利点ですし…
To think that a good virus ends
up becoming a real disease...
善玉ウイルスが本物の病原菌に化けるとはな
We thought it was an iron wall that
protected our food self-sufficiency,
食料自給を守る鉄の壁かと思っていたら
but it turned out to be a
double-edged sword.
実は諸刃の剣だったわけだ
Go.
出してくれ
"Jesus told them another parable:
「イエスは別の例えを持ち出して言われた」
'The kingdom of heaven is like a man
who sowed good seed in his field.
「天の国は次のように例えられる ある人が良い種を畑に播いた」
But while everyone was sleeping,
his enemy came
「人々が眠っている間に敵が来て
麦の中に毒麦を播いて行った」
and sowed weeds among
the wheat, and went away.'"
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒 ASUKA    校对:西西    时间轴:葛蔓     压制：娜夏
#21 Blood-Stained Reward
The security is still active...
セキュリティーは生きてる
Where can I find another way in?
他に入れそうな場所は…
Well, well...
Dammit! What a huge place...
くそ…何て広さだ
It's a factory that centrally
manages the defense virus
北陸全域に配給するための防御ウイルスを
in order to distribute it to
the entire Hokuriku area, so...
一括管理している工場ですからね
To think that such a large-scale facility
これだけの規模の設備が完全無人化されたまま稼働してるなんてな…
can continue to operate
in a fully automated manner...
The bigger the prey,
the easier it is to target.
図体が大きい獲物ほど狙いやすい
鯨も殺すほどの毒針を使うとなれば　なおさら…
Especially when you're using a
poisoned needle that could kill a whale...
This sort of tactic is just like Makishima.
槙島らしい戦術ですよ
It's probably from Mr. Kogami.
多分狡噛さんです
He probably saw us land. He's nearby.
私たちが着陸するのが見えたんでしょう
彼もすぐ近くにいます
Tsunemori speaking.
常守です
I didn't expect you to get here so soon.
思いの外早いお出ましだったな
Don't underestimate the MWPSB.
公安局を舐めないでください
You're not the only one who can
drive Makishima into a corner.
あなただけが槙島を追い詰められるわけじゃありません
He's already inside the facility.
やつはもう　施設内に入ってる
Using the equipment
Kudama left in the lab,
おそらく　管巻がラボに残していった機材を使い
he must be already adjusting
the Uka-no-Mitama virus by now.
ウカノミタマの調整に取り掛かっているはずだ
Or he might even be done.
あるいは もう終わらせているかも…
We're not going to let him have his way.
あの男の思いどおりにはさせません
Then we've gotta be quick.
だとしたら時間がない
Before he distributes the
Uka-no-Mitama that he tampered with,
やつが弄ったウカノミタマを撒き散らす前に
we have to shut down the entire facility.
ここの施設そのものを停止させるしかない
公安局の権限でこの施設への電力供給を遮断できるはずだな
Using the authority of the MWPSB,
you should be able to cut off
the power to this facility, right?
If we do that, it will shut down
not only the center's functions,
その場合 センターの機能だけでなく
but the security system as well.
セキュリティーシステムも全滅です
That's what you want, isn't it?
あなたの狙いはそれですね
You're trying to use us to lift the security
私たちを利用して セキュリティーを解除させ
so that you can beat us to
Makishima and kill him, aren't you?
先回りして槙島を殺すつもりでしょう
We'll never allow you to do that.
やらせませんよ　絶対に…
Makishima is trying
to destroy this country.
槙島はこの国を潰す気でいる
The MWPSB has
only one choice right now.
今公安局が選べる選択肢は一つだけだ
電力を止めろ
Stop the power.
Then this country will be saved.
それでこの国が救われる
I will save you, too.
私はあなたも救います
狡噛慎也を殺人犯にはさせません
I will not make
Shinya Kogami a murderer.
Then, I guess the
early bird gets the worm.
なら早い者勝ちだな
Can't we have the authority for
just the security system transferred to us
この施設 セキュリティーシステムの権限だけ
from the Ministry
of Agriculture and Forestry?
農林省から委譲してもらうわけにはいかないんですか
The process will take time.
手続きに時間を食う
Makishima might put us
in check while we're working on it.
その隙に槙島が王手をかけるかもしれん
We have no other choice but to
stop the facility itself, like Kogami said.
ここは狡噛の言うとおり
施設そのものを停止させるしか手はない
Kunizuka?
六合塚
I've already disabled the command
to switch to the secondary power supply.
予備電源への切り替えコマンドは凍結済みです
All we have to do now is to stop
the power from the power plant.
後は発電所からの送電を止めるだけ
There's something I'd like to ask you.
一つ確認させてください
When you encounter Mr. Kogami,
もし狡噛さんと遭遇した時 犯罪係数が３００を超えて
if his Crime Coefficient is over
300 and the Eliminator is activated,
エリミネーターが起動するようなら
please refrain from
shooting him and call me in.
発砲を控えて私を呼んでください
What's the point of calling you in?
君を呼んでどうなる
狡噛さん相手には切り札があります
I've got a trump card
I can use against Mr. Kogami.
Don't worry. Please leave it to me.
大丈夫　任せてください
Now we'll go after Makishima.
You'll help us, right?
私たちはこれから槙島聖護を追う
協力してくれるわよね
Of course.
「無論です」
Then... lock this gun in Paralyzer
mode with the safety unlocked.
ならこの銃 セーフティーを解除したまま
機能をパラライザーに固定して
You can do it, right?
できるでしょ
The Dominator decides
its enforcement mode
「ドミネーターは計測した犯罪係数に基づいて
based on the measured
Crime Coefficients.
執行モードが決定されます」
This is the basis for the system
that maintains the current public safety
「これは 現在の治安維持の根幹であり
and is inviolable.
不可侵のシステムです」
In order to fight Makishima,
we need suitably strong weapons.
槙島に立ち向かうには それ相応の強力な武器がいる
We do have to
protect ourselves, too.
私たちだって自分の身は守らなきゃならない
If we can't use the Dominators,
we have no choice
もしドミネーターが使えないなら
but to depend on more primitive weapons.
より原始的な武器に頼るしかなくなるわ
最悪の場合…
In the worst case, we may end up
killing Makishima with those weapons.
それで槙島を殺す羽目になるかもしれない
If that happens, that would be
because you lack resourcefulness.
「それはあなた方の 自助努力の欠落によるものです」
Our abilities are
limited and the likelihood
私たちの能力には限界があるし
that we will capture Makishima
alive without problems falls short of 100%.
槙島を無事確保できる確率は １００％には及ばないわ
If you guys grant an exception here,
that likelihood can be improved a little.
ここであなたたちが一つ特例を認めれば
その確率を少し改善できる
Think what the best decision is.
何が最善の判断か
考えてみなさいよ
You're good at calculating
risk and reward, right?
損得勘定は得意でしょ
From now until
Shogo Makishima is captured,
「現時点より 槙島聖護捕獲の達成に至るまで
we will grant an exception
on the applicable terminal device.
該当する端末装置の特例を許可します」
The safety will always stay unlocked.
「セーフティー　常時解除」
Mode is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
「モード ノンリーサル·パラライザー」
However, please pay close
attention to how you use it
「ただし 他の捜査官には露見しないよう
so that the other
detectives will not find out.
運用には 細心の注意を払ってください」
I know.
分かってるわ
Say, Missy.
おい　お嬢ちゃん…
局長に呼び出されてから こっちちょっと変だぞ
You've been acting strange
since the Chief called you in.
I don't know what happened,
何があったのか知らないが
but isn't the burden too
much for you to carry alone?
何もかもしょい込み過ぎじゃないのか
Are you worried?
心配ですか
Yeah, you're acting
the same as Kogami did.
ああ　狡噛の時と一緒だ
突っ走り過ぎた監視官の末路なんて
I don't wanna see any more
Inspectors meet their end
because they pushed too hard.
俺はそう何度も見たかない
Then would you like to
check my Crime Coefficient?
それなら 私の犯罪係数確かめてみます
おいおい…
Hey, hey...
It's okay. Please point the
Dominator at me.
構いません
ドミネーターを向けてみてください
I'll delete the record using
my authority as an Inspector.
記録は監視官権限で削除しますから
Crime Coefficient is 24.
「犯罪係数　２４」
An Inspector registered at the
Criminal Investigation Department.
「刑事課 登録監視官」
See? Right now,
I'm someone the System wants.
ねっ　今の私はシステムの望みどおりの人間なんですよ
Yeah...
Well then, Miss Kunizuka, please do it.
じゃあ六合塚さん　お願いします
Okay. I'll cut off the
power to the entire facility.
了解
施設全域への送電をカットします
Not bad, MWPSB...
やってくれるな　公安局…
Here goes!
よし
In any case, Makishima's
bio-terrorism has now completely failed.
ともかく槙島のバイオテロはこれで完全に失敗だ
If he's levelheaded, wouldn't he
start thinking about fleeing right away?
冷静な判断力があれば すぐさま逃げ出す算段を打つんじゃないか
I'm not so sure about that.
そうでしょうか
It's true that Makishima's actions
have been carefully carried out,
槙島のこれまでの行動は確かに周到でしたけど
but I don't think that necessarily
means everything is a calculation to him.
損得勘定だけでは割り切れなかった気がします
Are you saying that he'll
still stick to his plan even now?
この期に及んで あいつがまだ粘ると
If there is a way...
The emergency power supply...
手があるとすれば…非常電源
Right now,
今はまだ 外部からのコマンドで切り替えを遮断してるだけですよね
we're just blocking the emergency
power from the outside, right?
Right.
ええ
Then it can be manually rebooted
via the control board inside the facility.
だったら　施設内の制御盤から手動で再起動をかければいい
That's his only chance
for getting the power back.
もう一度電力を取り戻すチャンスはそこしかない
The central control room...
Should we cast a net around it?
中央管制室か…
網を張るか
Wait.
待て
There's still a good chance
that he'd run without fighting.
素直に逃げ出す公算だってじゅうぶんにある
We don't have time to make a side trip.
寄り道はしていられないぞ
Let's split in two.
二手に分かれましょう
私は管制室に
I'll go to the control room.
Mr. Ginoza, please
check the university's lab.
宜野座さんは大学のラボを当たってください
I'll go with Inspector Tsunemori.
私は常守監視官に同伴します
警備責任者のコンソールから本部の志恩と連携すれば
If we work with Shion at Headquarters
via the main security console,
we might at least be able to
control this facility's security cameras.
せめて施設の監視カメラぐらいは こちらでも制御できるかも
Then, we'll be in charge
of chasing him, huh?
となると　追いかけっこは俺たちのコンビだな
Come on, don't make that face.
Guys should take on the rough stuff.
そう嫌そうな顔をするな
荒事は男が引き受けるもんさ
Dammit!
くそっ
Did something happen
at the Ministry of Welfare?
厚生省で　何かあったんですか
そんなふうに見えますか
Does it seem that way?
今のあなたは誰よりも前向きなのに
You're being the most
constructive of everyone right now,
and yet you look the
most depressed of all of us.
誰よりも落ち込んでいるふうに見えます
立ち止まっていても何一つ解決しない
Stopping here wouldn't resolve anything.
今はただ進むしかない
I just have to move forward.
どんなに小さくても希望はある
No matter how small
it may be, there's still hope.
As long as I don't give up on it,
それを諦めないかぎり
私は最後まで刑事のままでいられる
I can continue to be
a detective until the end.
When you joined
us as a new Inspector,
新しい監視官がやって来たとき
at first I thought you
were a naive little girl
最初は甘そうなお嬢ちゃんだと思いました
and that you couldn't
possibly be fit for the job.
こんな仕事はとうてい勤まらないって
うん　そうだったかも…
Yeah, I might've been like that.
But my impression back
then was completely wrong.
でも　あのときの印象は完全に間違っていた
今ならそう断言できる
I'm sure of that now.
あなたになら命を預けられます　常守さん
I can entrust my life to you,
Miss Tsunemori.
買いかぶり過ぎですよ
You overestimate my abilities.
Clear.
クリア
Did we make it... in time?
間に合った…のかな
でも　ここにホントに槙島が？
But is Makishima
really going to be here?
That's right... It's strange
that there's no one here.
そうか…誰もいないなんて変だ
What?
えっ
He would foresee Makishima's
actions more accurately than me.
彼なら私よりも正確に槙島の動きを予測する
If this was the correct answer,
これが正解だったなら
狡噛さんが先回りしてなきゃおかしいわ
I'd expect Mr. Kogami to have
made it here before us.
どうして…
Why?
I feel like I'm
overlooking something.
何か見落としてる気がする
I have to check something with you.
一つ 確かめておかなきゃならない
What's bothering you at a time like this?
こんなときに どうした
狡噛の逃亡をほう助したな
You helped Kogami escape, didn't you?
あんまり老いぼれをいじめんでくれんか
Would you try not to
be hard on an old man?
あんたは狡噛が罪を引っかぶることで
You think that by Kogami
taking the crime upon himself,
evil will be defeated as a result.
結果として悪がついえると思ってる
それがあんたのような時代遅れの猟犬の
That's the savage, selfish justice
of an old-fashioned hunting dog like yourself.
野蛮で身勝手な正義感だ
違うか
Am I wrong?
結局　頼りにしてるのは狡噛だ
Kogami really is the one you rely on.
俺には何も期待してない
You don't expect anything from me.
You think that there's no chance
I can capture Makishima, don't you?
槙島を捕らえられる見込みなんてないと思ってるんだろ
Kogami is a latent criminal and Enforcer.
He and I are two of a kind.
あの男も潜在犯で執行官
俺と同じ穴のむじなだよ
But you're still taking
a different path than we are.
だが　お前は今でも違う道を歩み続けてる
それでよかったと心底　俺は思ってる
I think that's for the best
from the bottom of my heart.
How could you make
a justification like that?
よくもそんな奇麗事が言えたもんだ
犯人が逃げて刑事が追う…
A culprit runs and detectives go after him...
That's our assumption.
それが私たちの先入観
監視官
Inspector?
でも槙島の見方は違う
But Makishima looks
at things differently.
あいつは今私たちがどれだけ窮地に立たされてるか
He understands how much of
a bind we're in better than we do.
私たち以上に理解してる…
Mr. Ginoza and
Mr. Masaoka are in danger!
宜野座さんたちが危ない
Please wait!
It's dangerous to go by yourself!
待ってください
１人では危険です
You stay here. If Makishima comes,
あなたは残って…もし槙島が来ても
don't let him touch the
emergency power supply at any cost!
絶対に非常電源に触らせちゃ駄目
If push comes to shove,
you can even destroy the whole console!
いざとなったらコンソールごと破壊して構わないから
Mr. Ginoza! Inspector Ginoza?!
宜野座さん　宜野座監視官
Wait!
待て
Nobuchika!
伸元
Dammit!
くそ…
待ってろ
Hold on!
Behind you!
後ろだ
You bastard!
このーっ
道連れに自爆しようってのか
Are you trying to blow yourself
up and take me with you?
You think I'd do a stupid thing like that?
そんなつまらないことをすると思うかい
絶対にその男を放すな　執行官
Don't let that man
go at any cost, Enforcer!
You are a detective!
Fulfill your duty!
あんたは刑事だ
その務めを果たせ
とっつぁん…
Pops!
Y... You idiot!
バカヤロー
何で犯人を逃がした
Why did you let
the culprit get away?!
何で…
Why?!
あんたはデカだろ
You're a detective, aren't you?!
There's nothing good
about being a detective.
デカなんて…
ろくなもんじゃねえよ…
You are my son after all.
やっぱ親子なんだな
Your eyes...
look just the same as mine...
目元なんざ
若いころの俺に…
...when I was young.
そっくりだ…
Dad...
親父…
Dad!
親父ーっ
Why?! Why?!
何でだ
何で…
It's too late!
遅過ぎるだろうがーっ
So you finally ditched that fake justice
ついにまがい物の正義を捨てて
and now you've got
some real bloodlust, huh?
本物の殺意を手に取ったか
You are everything
I hoped you would be after all.
やはり　君は僕が期待したとおりの男だった
Really?
そうかい
I have no hopes for you at all, though.
だが　俺は貴様に何の期待もしちゃいない
Don't be so indifferent
after coming this far.
ここまで来てつれないことを言ってくれるなよ
いい気になるな
Don't be so arrogant.
You're not a special person or anything.
貴様は特別な人間なんかじゃない
ただ世の中から無視されてきただけのゴミくずだ
You're just trash that's been
ignored by society all this time.
たった一人で人の輪を外れて
You feel bitter for having been rejected
and left out of the community, don't you?
爪はじきにされてきたのが恨めしいんだろ
貴様は孤独に耐えられなかっただけだ
You just couldn't bear solitude, that's all.
仲間外れは嫌だって泣きわめいてるガキと変わらない
You're no different from a kid
whining about not wanting to be left out.
面白いことを言うな
You sure say some funny things.
Solitude? Does that apply only to me?
孤独だと？
それは僕に限った話か？
この社会に孤独でない人間など誰がいる
Who isn't alone in this society?
他者とのつながりが自我の基盤だった時代など
The time when our connection to others
was the basis of our selves is long gone.
とうの昔に終わっている
In this world where everyone
is watched over by the system
誰もがシステムに見守られ
システムの規範に沿って生きる世界には
and live within the system's standards,
a community isn't necessary.
人の輪なんて必要ない
Everyone just lives in their own little cell,
みんな小さな独房の中で
and the system tames them by giving
them each their own personal serenity.
自分だけの安らぎに飼いならされているだけだ
There's no way that I could love someone
But I want someone to love me
Even if yesterday could
continue unchanging into forever
You and I would never get anywhere
God... where did you go?
I don't hear any response,
but that's how it always is
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I'll go with you
No matter the sin,
I'll bear the burden for you
I'll walk an uncharted path
All alone with you
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.